<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Preserve Starry Skies on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/</link><description>Recent content in Preserve Starry Skies on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Starry Skies South. All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lighting for Starry Skies</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</guid><description>We advocate the International Dark-Sky Association&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;
Five Principles for Responsible Outdoor Lighting If light is deemed useful and necessary, follow these guidelines to prevent, or when that’s not possible, minimize light pollution:
USEFUL – All light should have a clear purpose. Before installing or replacing a light, determine if light is needed. Consider how the use of light will impact the area, including wildlife and the environment. Consider using reflective paints or self-luminous markers for signs, curbs, and steps to reduce the need for permanently installed outdoor lighting.</description></item><item><title>Environmental Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</guid><description>Find out why humans, plants, and nonhuman animals need starry skies by watching the below videos and reading the provided resources.
Humans Read more about why darkness at night is important for human health here.
Plants and Nonhuman Animals Read more about why darkness at night is important for plant and animals like bird, sea turtle, and insect health here.
Additional Resources Want to learn how specific living organisms are affected by light pollution in more detail?</description></item><item><title>Social Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</guid><description>Duis neque nisi, dapibus sed mattis et quis, nibh. Sed et dapibus nisl amet mattis, sed a rutrum accumsan sed. Suspendisse eu.
Suspendisse laoreet metus ut metus imperdiet interdum aliquam justo tincidunt.</description></item></channel></rss>