<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Member Profiles on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/</link><description>Recent content in Member Profiles on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Starry Skies South. All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr. Michelle Wooten</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</guid><description>Michelle is an Assistant Professor of Astronomy Education at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. She welcomes the world of astronomy to hundreds of non-science majors each semester. Dr. Wooten is also an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate and is leading organization of efforts to address light pollution and promote dark skies across the southeastern United States in collective form.</description></item><item><title>Dr. William Baker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</guid><description>I was born (in 1959) and raised in Birmingham, leaving only in 1981 to attend Medical School and then my residency in Anesthesiology. I returned with my wife in 1989, knowing that Birmingham is a great place to raise a family. I worked as an anesthesiologist until retiring in 2019.
I was a child of the Space Race era, and became interested in astronomy and astrophotography at a young age. I bought my first “real” telescope at age 13, after saving my earnings from neighborhood lawn-mowing services.</description></item><item><title>Meaghan Walsh Gerard</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</guid><description>Meaghan was born in Illinois, then grew up along the east coast. Skiing in New England, hiking in Yellowstone, kayaking in Maine and exploring Viking settlements in Newfoundland were all part of a childhood filled with outdoor adventures.
After graduating from college in New Hampshire with a bachelor’s degree in English, she moved to a much less snowy Savannah. While managing a performing arts and historic site nonprofit, she earned a master’s degree in cinema studies.</description></item><item><title>Meribeth Camp</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</guid><description>I have selfish reasons to keep my skies as natural as possible. I learned in Astronomy Class at UAB my family deals with light trespass from a neighboring park. I have a small child, and it’s proven hard to trick her into thinking it was nighttime when floodlights are shining in her room. This class inspired me to create positive change in my community. I have joined Starry Skies South in my area, and I encourage others to advocate for their areas as well.</description></item><item><title>Jeff Allegrezza</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</guid><description>I had a small Sears refractor when I was a kid. I can remember seeing the Milky Way from my suburban driveway. Forty years later, I see only the brightest stars from my house in Birmingham.
I enjoy living in Birmingham. I take advantage of the great restaurants, the mountains, the natural beauty, and the history. But I miss the stars. If I grew up now, I wouldn’t even realize the splendor of a dark sky.</description></item><item><title>Jim Tucker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jim-tucker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jim-tucker/</guid><description>I have always been fascinated with science and space. My parents took me to a total solar eclipse when I was nine years old and I’ve been hooked ever since. I built a ten inch Dobsonian telescope in anticipation of the return of Halley’s comet in 1986, that was a dud as far as appearances, but it got me involved in the astronomy hobby and led to me joining the Birmingham Astronomical Society (BAS).</description></item><item><title>Greg Harber</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</guid><description>My interest in dark skies is primarily influenced by the effects of light pollution on migrating birds, many of which migrate at night.
I grew up in Fort Lauderdale, FL and can recall as a child being able to sit on the roof of our house and watch the nighttime launches of the space missions as they headed skyward from the launch pads at Cape Canaveral - a distance of approximately 180 miles.</description></item><item><title>Marlena Wald</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</guid><description>The ‘space race’ began when I was in the second grade. Every grade after that brought more science education in the schools, the excitement of NASA launches, and an overall interest in Earth’s Moon and the stars. My Sears telescope arrived as a tenth birthday present, and since then I have never stopped observing. My childhood friends and I were space ‘fans’. After school we drank Tang and ate Space Sticks while watching The Adventures of Rocky and Bullwinkle and Friends/.</description></item></channel></rss>