<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Member Profiles on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/</link><description>Recent content in Member Profiles on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Starry Skies South. All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr. Michelle Wooten</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</guid><description>Michelle is an Assistant Professor of Astronomy Education at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. She welcomes the world of astronomy to hundreds of non-science majors each semester. Dr. Wooten is also an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate and is leading organization of efforts to address light pollution and promote dark skies across the southeastern United States in collective form.</description></item><item><title>Dr. William Baker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</guid><description>I was born (in 1959) and raised in Birmingham, leaving only in 1981 to attend Medical School and then my residency in Anesthesiology. I returned with my wife in 1989, knowing that Birmingham is a great place to raise a family. I worked as an anesthesiologist until retiring in 2019.
I was a child of the Space Race era, and became interested in astronomy and astrophotography at a young age. I bought my first “real” telescope at age 13, after saving my earnings from neighborhood lawn-mowing services.</description></item><item><title>Meaghan Walsh Gerard</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</guid><description>Meaghan was born in Illinois, then grew up along the east coast. Skiing in New England, hiking in Yellowstone, kayaking in Maine and exploring Viking settlements in Newfoundland were all part of a childhood filled with outdoor adventures.
After graduating from college in New Hampshire with a bachelor’s degree in English, she moved to a much less snowy Savannah. While managing a performing arts and historic site nonprofit, she earned a master’s degree in cinema studies.</description></item><item><title>Meribeth Camp</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</guid><description>I have selfish reasons to keep my skies as natural as possible. I learned in Astronomy Class at UAB my family deals with light trespass from a neighboring park. I have a small child, and it’s proven hard to trick her into thinking it was nighttime when floodlights are shining in her room. This class inspired me to create positive change in my community. I have joined Starry Skies South in my area, and I encourage others to advocate for their areas as well.</description></item></channel></rss>