<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Starry Skies South</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr. Michelle Wooten</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</guid><description>Michelle is an Assistant Professor of Astronomy Education at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. She welcomes the world of astronomy to hundreds of non-science majors each semester. Dr. Wooten is also an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate and is leading organization of efforts to address light pollution and promote dark skies across the southeastern United States in collective form.</description></item><item><title>Dr. William Baker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</guid><description>I was born (in 1959) and raised in Birmingham, leaving only in 1981 to attend Medical School and then my residency in Anesthesiology. I returned with my wife in 1989, knowing that Birmingham is a great place to raise a family. I worked as an anesthesiologist until retiring in 2019.
I was a child of the Space Race era, and became interested in astronomy and astrophotography at a young age. I bought my first “real” telescope at age 13, after saving my earnings from neighborhood lawn-mowing services.</description></item><item><title>Meaghan Walsh Gerard</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</guid><description>Meaghan was born in Illinois, then grew up along the east coast. Skiing in New England, hiking in Yellowstone, kayaking in Maine and exploring Viking settlements in Newfoundland were all part of a childhood filled with outdoor adventures.
After graduating from college in New Hampshire with a bachelor’s degree in English, she moved to a much less snowy Savannah. While managing a performing arts and historic site nonprofit, she earned a master’s degree in cinema studies.</description></item><item><title>Meribeth Camp</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</guid><description>I have selfish reasons to keep my skies as natural as possible. I learned in Astronomy Class at UAB my family deals with light trespass from a neighboring park. I have a small child, and it’s proven hard to trick her into thinking it was nighttime when floodlights are shining in her room. This class inspired me to create positive change in my community. I have joined Starry Skies South in my area, and I encourage others to advocate for their areas as well.</description></item><item><title>Dawn-Michelle Oliver</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dawn-michelle-oliver-north-carolina-member/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dawn-michelle-oliver-north-carolina-member/</guid><description>My husband and I have lived in rural Caswell County, NC, for the past 20 years and the night has always been beautifully dark – filled with bright stars, moon shadows, spring peepers, whip-poor-wills, luna moths, and fireflies. But as everywhere, the area is changing quickly with the arrival of exceptionally bright LED floodlights.
I’m a stargazer and passionate nature lover, and I believe the night environment in Caswell County, and across the southeast, is a treasure we must cherish and protect for ourselves and for all the creatures who share it with us.</description></item><item><title>Jeff Allegrezza</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</guid><description>I had a small Sears refractor when I was a kid. I can remember seeing the Milky Way from my suburban driveway. Forty years later, I see only the brightest stars from my house in Birmingham.
I enjoy living in Birmingham. I take advantage of the great restaurants, the mountains, the natural beauty, and the history. But I miss the stars. If I grew up now, I wouldn’t even realize the splendor of a dark sky.</description></item><item><title>Marlena Wald</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</guid><description>The ‘space race’ began when I was in the second grade. Every grade after that brought more science education in the schools, the excitement of NASA launches, and an overall interest in Earth’s Moon and the stars. My Sears telescope arrived as a tenth birthday present, and since then I have never stopped observing. My childhood friends and I were space ‘fans’. After school we drank Tang and ate Space Sticks while watching The Adventures of Rocky and Bullwinkle and Friends/.</description></item><item><title>Mel Blake</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/mel-blake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/mel-blake/</guid><description>Mel Blake Associate Professor University of North Alabama Director, UNA Planetarium Florence, Alabama
I grew up seeing the Milky Way in my backyard and it would be a shame to be the last generation to be able to say that. As a professional astronomer, dark skies are essential for collecting good quality data for studying the universe. As someone who enjoys the outdoors, having pristine views of the sky at night is important and helps inspire the next generation of astronomers, and helps with public support for astronomy.</description></item><item><title>Sara Johnson</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/sara-johnson/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/sara-johnson/</guid><description>I became interested in dark sky advocacy primarily as a birder, and my concern for migrating birds through our lit and altered landscape. Through my work at the Champaign County Audubon Society, I began working with local organizations to begin a regional dark sky week and &amp;ldquo;Lights Out for Migration&amp;rdquo; campaign. I think that light pollution is a serious but overlooked problem, as we, as humans, have trouble noticing small and gradual change.</description></item><item><title>Mission &amp; Scope</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</guid><description>The above photo was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
Mission Our mission is to promote appreciation and preservation of starry skies across the southeastern United States.
Background &amp;amp; Scope In April 2022, Dr. Michelle Wooten, an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate in Alabama, invited the astronomy clubs of Alabama to meet together to form a dark-sky advocacy collective. Over the next few months we (i) applied to become an International Dark-Sky Association (IDA) chapter, (ii) voted to change our state-based focused to a regional focus spanning the Southeastern United States without an IDA chapter, and (iii) voted on our collective&amp;rsquo;s name, Starry Skies South.</description></item><item><title>Our Region</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</guid><description>Our region includes Mississippi, Alabama, Georgia, North Carolina*, and South Carolina. We welcome participants from other places across the southeastern United States, per their interest. To participate, membership to DarkSky International is recommended but not required.
*﻿North Carolina also has a state-based chapter, DarkSky North Carolina. Some members in DarkSky NC also participate in Starry Skies South.</description></item><item><title>Partner Organizations</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</guid><description>Learn about the groups with whom we are partnered.</description></item><item><title>Members in the News</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</guid><description>The above image was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
November 2022 Tom Berta&amp;rsquo;s article, Call to action for dark skies again is published in the Charleston City Paper.
September 2022 Tom Berta&amp;rsquo;s commentary, Bad street lighting is a problem. This is how we can fix it is posted in the Post and Courier.
June 2022 Our South Carolina coordinator, Tom Berta, is interviewed about light pollution in WCBD News 2 Charleston.</description></item><item><title>Christina Rogers</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/christina-rogers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/christina-rogers/</guid><description>Christina Rogers, RNC-NIC, BS Biology
When I was a teenager, after graduating high school, my friend and I rented a car to drive up the coast of California. He was the nervous type, so I was the one driving at night and when there were a lot of semi trucks driving by he asked me to pull over for a little bit so he could relax for a minute. I pulled over and stepped out of the car.</description></item><item><title>Tom Berta</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/tom-berta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/tom-berta/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m from southern West Virginia coal fields where the night sky was always dark and you could see the milk way and more without light pollution! I now live in the Lowcountry, Charleston South Carolina. I have been an amateur astronomer since I was a little kid, dreaming about going into space, thanks partly to NASA. In high school, I joined the rocket club, the teacher Mike McGuire who taught science in high school was an amateur astronomer and I was hooked.</description></item><item><title>Find Starry Skies</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/locations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/locations/</guid><description>Our members&amp;rsquo; favorite places to observe starry skies are&amp;hellip;
Alabama Cheaha State Park Flagg Mountain, Sylacauga Chilatchee Creek Campground, Alberta Camp McDowell, Nauvoo Pine Apple Moundville Archaeological Park P﻿erry Lakes Park Florida Blackwater State Forest Lutz Georgia Brasstown Blad Watson Mill Bridge State Park Ocmulee National Park &amp;amp; Preserve Hancock and Warren counties Hard Labor Creek State Park Deerlick Astronomy Village Stephen C. Foster State Park - International Dark Sky Park Designation Monticello Blue Ridge Mississippi French Camp (Mid-South Stargaze and Astronomy Conference - Rainwater Observatory) N﻿orth Carolina B﻿rown Mountain Overlook S﻿outh Mountain State Park South Carolina John&amp;rsquo;s Island County Park Hamption Plantation State Historic Site (applied for IDSP status) T﻿able Rock State Park D﻿evil Fork State Park O﻿conee State Park C﻿herry Hill National Forest Campground Tennessee South Cumberland State Park The above image is World Atlas 2015 overlay data sourced from Falchi, Fabio; Cinzano, Pierantonio; Duriscoe, Dan; Kyba, Christopher C.</description></item><item><title>Acknowledgements</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</guid><description>The above photo was taken at Cheaha State Park during the event Discovering Dazzling New Depths of Dark Skies in April 2022.
Many thanks to&amp;hellip;
Ellyn Grady (University of Alabama at Birmingham) for providing tips and resources for getting our non-profit paperwork started the staff at Cheaha State Park, Oak Mountain State Park, University of Montevallo&amp;rsquo;s James Wylie Shepherd Observatory, and Samford University&amp;rsquo;s Christenberry Planetarium for partnering with us on public programming for International Dark-Sky Week 2022 dark-sky advocates Brent and Dawn Davis for supporting guidelines on dark-sky park creation procedures Maggie Johnston, Director of Wild Alabama, for supporting information on nonprofit organization and development within Alabama.</description></item><item><title>Lighting for Starry Skies</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</guid><description>We advocate the International Dark-Sky Association&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;
Five Principles for Responsible Outdoor Lighting If light is deemed useful and necessary, follow these guidelines to prevent, or when that’s not possible, minimize light pollution:
USEFUL – All light should have a clear purpose. Before installing or replacing a light, determine if light is needed. Consider how the use of light will impact the area, including wildlife and the environment. Consider using reflective paints or self-luminous markers for signs, curbs, and steps to reduce the need for permanently installed outdoor lighting.</description></item><item><title>Environmental Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</guid><description>The above image, titled &amp;ldquo;Dusk over south end of Tybee Island, Georgia,&amp;rdquo; was photographed by Starry Skies South member Meaghan Walsh Gerard (Georgia).
Find out why humans, plants, and nonhuman animals need starry skies by watching the below videos and reading the provided resources.
W﻿ritten by Starry Skies South member Dr. William Baker.
Humans Lighting for starry skies is beneficial to human health. We&amp;rsquo;ve described this in the Social Benefits section of our website, and you can also learn more in the video below and here.</description></item><item><title>Social Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</guid><description>The above image of M42, a nebula in Orion, was photographed by Mississippi member Mickey Fratesi.
Written by Starry Skies South member Dr. William Baker
Light pollution is a “real thing”. Even if you don’t care about looking at the wonder that is the night sky, you should be concerned about light pollution (LP). It turns out that Light Pollution is negatively affecting you in more ways than you know.</description></item><item><title>Joe Kutner</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/joe-kutner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/joe-kutner/</guid><description>Joe is an amateur astronomer and member of the Von Braun Astronomical Society in Huntsville, AL. His interest in preserving our dark skies began when he heard Tim Hunter give a talk at the Texas Star Party about his time as the president of the International Dark-Sky Association.</description></item><item><title>Greg Harber</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</guid><description>My interest in dark skies is primarily influenced by the effects of light pollution on migrating birds, many of which migrate at night.
I grew up in Fort Lauderdale, FL and can recall as a child being able to sit on the roof of our house and watch the nighttime launches of the space missions as they headed skyward from the launch pads at Cape Canaveral - a distance of approximately 180 miles.</description></item><item><title>Outreach &amp; Events</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/events/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/events/</guid><description>Our monthly meetings take place virtually on the first Thursday of every month at 7 p.m. Central Time (8 p.m. Eastern). If you would like to join our next meeting, please email info@starryskiessouth.org</description></item><item><title>Michael Buford</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michael-buford/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michael-buford/</guid><description>I have been involved in astronomy ever since I was a child, volunteering with the Von Braun Astronomical Society (VBAS) on Monte Sano Mountain in Huntsville, Alabama. I found that in showing others how to find things in the night sky, as well as educating them on the damage we are doing to the night&amp;rsquo;s beauty. The skies have gotten steadily worse in Huntsville overall as the city expands, so too do the lights.</description></item><item><title>Follow Us</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/follow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/follow/</guid><description>News Blog Social Media Instagram: @starryskiessouth Facebook: @starryskiessouth Contact Info info @ starryskiessouth.org</description></item><item><title>Millie Finch</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/millie-finch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/millie-finch/</guid><description>I am deeply passionate about preserving dark skies and reducing light pollution for the benefit of both humans and the natural world. I recognize that the artificial lighting that permeates our cities and suburbs not only obscures our view of the stars, but also disrupts the circadian rhythms of humans and animals, affecting their health and behavior. I understand that light pollution can have negative impacts on ecosystems, particularly nocturnal animals and insects, and disrupts the balance of the natural world.</description></item><item><title>Charlie Finch</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/charlie-finch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/charlie-finch/</guid><description>Charlie is an astronomer conducting research at the U.S. Naval Observatory in Washington D.C. but presently residing in Georgia. He attained his Masters in Astronomy from Georgia State University, with a focus on astrometry and nearby stars. In his leisure time, Charlie enjoys hiking, kayaking, exploring nature, stargazing, and sipping stellar coffee.</description></item></channel></rss>