<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Starry Skies South. All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dr. Michelle Wooten</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/michelle-wooten/</guid><description>Michelle is an Assistant Professor of Astronomy Education at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. She welcomes the world of astronomy to hundreds of non-science majors each semester. Dr. Wooten is also an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate and is leading organization of efforts to address light pollution and promote dark skies across the southeastern United States in collective form.</description></item><item><title>Dr. William Baker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/dr-william-baker/</guid><description>I was born (in 1959) and raised in Birmingham, leaving only in 1981 to attend Medical School and then my residency in Anesthesiology. I returned with my wife in 1989, knowing that Birmingham is a great place to raise a family. I worked as an anesthesiologist until retiring in 2019.
I was a child of the Space Race era, and became interested in astronomy and astrophotography at a young age. I bought my first “real” telescope at age 13, after saving my earnings from neighborhood lawn-mowing services.</description></item><item><title>Meaghan Walsh Gerard</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meaghan-walsh-gerard/</guid><description>Meaghan was born in Illinois, then grew up along the east coast. Skiing in New England, hiking in Yellowstone, kayaking in Maine and exploring Viking settlements in Newfoundland were all part of a childhood filled with outdoor adventures.
After graduating from college in New Hampshire with a bachelor’s degree in English, she moved to a much less snowy Savannah. While managing a performing arts and historic site nonprofit, she earned a master’s degree in cinema studies.</description></item><item><title>Meribeth Camp</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/meribeth-camp/</guid><description>I have selfish reasons to keep my skies as natural as possible. I learned in Astronomy Class at UAB my family deals with light trespass from a neighboring park. I have a small child, and it’s proven hard to trick her into thinking it was nighttime when floodlights are shining in her room. This class inspired me to create positive change in my community. I have joined Starry Skies South in my area, and I encourage others to advocate for their areas as well.</description></item><item><title>Jeff Allegrezza</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jeff-allegrezza/</guid><description>I had a small Sears refractor when I was a kid. I can remember seeing the Milky Way from my suburban driveway. Forty years later, I see only the brightest stars from my house in Birmingham.
I enjoy living in Birmingham. I take advantage of the great restaurants, the mountains, the natural beauty, and the history. But I miss the stars. If I grew up now, I wouldn’t even realize the splendor of a dark sky.</description></item><item><title>Jim Tucker</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jim-tucker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/jim-tucker/</guid><description>I have always been fascinated with science and space. My parents took me to a total solar eclipse when I was nine years old and I’ve been hooked ever since. I built a ten inch Dobsonian telescope in anticipation of the return of Halley’s comet in 1986, that was a dud as far as appearances, but it got me involved in the astronomy hobby and led to me joining the Birmingham Astronomical Society (BAS).</description></item><item><title>Marlena Wald</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/marlena-wald/</guid><description>The ‘space race’ began when I was in the second grade. Every grade after that brought more science education in the schools, the excitement of NASA launches, and an overall interest in Earth’s Moon and the stars. My Sears telescope arrived as a tenth birthday present, and since then I have never stopped observing. My childhood friends and I were space ‘fans’. After school we drank Tang and ate Space Sticks while watching The Adventures of Rocky and Bullwinkle and Friends/.</description></item><item><title>Reed Prince</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/reed-prince/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/reed-prince/</guid><description>I got into the dark sky movement through my interest in joining the Birmingham Astronomical Society. My first contact with BAS was Michelle Wooten, the Alabama Delegate for the International Dark Sky Association. I had noticed for some time that the stars were becoming more and more invisible. I just did not realize how bad the situation was until I took a good look at the IDSA educational materials.
I am working on&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Mission &amp; Scope</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</guid><description>The above photo was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
Mission Our mission is to promote appreciation and conservation of starry skies across the southeastern United States.
Background &amp;amp; Scope In April 2022, Dr. Michelle Wooten, an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate in Alabama, invited the astronomy clubs of Alabama to meet together to form a dark-sky advocacy collective. Over the next few months we (i) applied to become an International Dark-Sky Association chapter, (ii) voted to change our state-based focused to a regional focus spanning the southeastern United States without an IDA chapter, and (iii) voted on our collective&amp;rsquo;s name, Starry Skies South.</description></item><item><title>Our Region</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</guid><description>Our proposed region includes Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, Georgia, and South Carolina.</description></item><item><title>Partner Organizations</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</guid><description>Learn about the groups with whom we are partnered.</description></item><item><title>Members in the News</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</guid><description>The above image was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
June 2022 Our South Carolina coordinator, Tom Berta, is interviewed about light pollution in WCBD News 2 Charleston. Watch the video here.
May 2022 The grant-funded initiative of Starry Skies South Lead, Dr. Wooten, focused on dark-sky curriculum development for astronomy courses at UAB is described in the UAB Reporter on May 18, 2022
April 2022 Starry Skies South Lead Dr.</description></item><item><title>Find Starry Skies</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/locations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/locations/</guid><description>Our members&amp;rsquo; favorite places to observe starry skies are&amp;hellip;
Alabama Cheaha State Park Flagg Mountain, Sylacauga Chilatchee Creek Campground, Alberta Camp McDowell, Nauvoo Pine Apple Moundville Archaeological Park Georgia Brasstown Blad Watson Mill Bridge State Park Ocmulee National Park &amp;amp; Preserve Hancock and Warren counties Hard Labor Creek State Park Deerlick Astronomy Village Stephen C. Foster State Park - International Dark Sky Park Designation Monticello Blue Ridge Mississippi French Camp (Mid-South Stargaze and Astronomy Conference - Rainwater Observatory) Florida Blackwater State Forest Lutz The above image is World Atlas 2015 overlay data sourced from Falchi, Fabio; Cinzano, Pierantonio; Duriscoe, Dan; Kyba, Christopher C.</description></item><item><title>Acknowledgements</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</guid><description>The above photo was taken at Cheaha State Park during the event Discovering Dazzling New Depths of Dark Skies in April 2022.
Many thanks to&amp;hellip;
Ellyn Grady (University of Alabama at Birmingham) for providing tips and resources for getting our non-profit paperwork started the staff at Cheaha State Park, Oak Mountain State Park, University of Montevallo&amp;rsquo;s James Wylie Shepherd Observatory, and Samford University&amp;rsquo;s Christenberry Planetarium for partnering with us on public programming for International Dark-Sky Week 2022 dark-sky advocates Brent and Dawn Davis for supporting guidelines on dark-sky park creation procedures Maggie Johnston, Director of Wild Alabama, for supporting information on nonprofit organization and development within Alabama.</description></item><item><title>Lighting for Starry Skies</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/lighting/</guid><description>We advocate the International Dark-Sky Association&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;
Five Principles for Responsible Outdoor Lighting If light is deemed useful and necessary, follow these guidelines to prevent, or when that’s not possible, minimize light pollution:
USEFUL – All light should have a clear purpose. Before installing or replacing a light, determine if light is needed. Consider how the use of light will impact the area, including wildlife and the environment. Consider using reflective paints or self-luminous markers for signs, curbs, and steps to reduce the need for permanently installed outdoor lighting.</description></item><item><title>Environmental Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/environment/</guid><description>The above image, titled &amp;ldquo;Dusk over south end of Tybee Island, Georgia,&amp;rdquo; was photographed by Starry Skies South member Meaghan Walsh Gerard (Georgia).
Find out why humans, plants, and nonhuman animals need starry skies by watching the below videos and reading the provided resources.
Humans Read more about why darkness at night is important for human health here.
Plants and Nonhuman Animals Read more about why darkness at night is important for plant and animals like bird, sea turtle, and insect health here.</description></item><item><title>Social Benefits</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/preserving/social/</guid><description>The above image of M42, a nebula in Orion, was photographed by Mississippi member Mickey Fratesi.
The Heritage of Starry Skies Starry skies have benefitted Earthen creatures - both health-wise and aesthetically - for centuries. Take a moment to take in the splendor of the night sky when it is seen without the effect of misdirected artificial light at night:
Energy Waste Humans spend several billions of dollars annually on misdirected artificial light at night.</description></item><item><title>Greg Harber</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members/greg-harber/</guid><description>My interest in dark skies is primarily influenced by the effects of light pollution on migrating birds, many of which migrate at night.
I grew up in Fort Lauderdale, FL and can recall as a child being able to sit on the roof of our house and watch the nighttime launches of the space missions as they headed skyward from the launch pads at Cape Canaveral - a distance of approximately 180 miles.</description></item><item><title>Outreach &amp; Events</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/events/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/events/</guid><description>Our monthly meetings take place virtually on the first Thursday of every month at 7 p.m. Central Time (8 p.m. Eastern).
Find us at the Alabama Audubon&amp;rsquo;s Black Belt Birding Festival on Friday, July 29.</description></item><item><title>Follow Us</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/follow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/follow/</guid><description>Social Media Twitter: @starryskysouth
Facebook: @starryskiessouth</description></item></channel></rss>