<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Us on Starry Skies South</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/</link><description>Recent content in About Us on Starry Skies South</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Starry Skies South</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mission &amp; Scope</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/mission/</guid><description>The above photo was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
Mission Our mission is to promote appreciation and preservation of starry skies across the southeastern United States.
Background &amp;amp; Scope In April 2022, Dr. Michelle Wooten, an International Dark-Sky Association Delegate in Alabama, invited the astronomy clubs of Alabama to meet together to form a dark-sky advocacy collective. Over the next few months we (i) applied to become an International Dark-Sky Association (IDA) chapter, (ii) voted to change our state-based focused to a regional focus spanning the Southeastern United States without an IDA chapter, and (iii) voted on our collective&amp;rsquo;s name, Starry Skies South.</description></item><item><title>Our Region</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/region/</guid><description>Our region includes Alabama, Georgia, Mississippi, North Carolina*, and South Carolina. We welcome participants from other places across the southeastern United States, per their interest. To participate, membership to DarkSky International is recommended but not required.
*﻿North Carolina also has a state-based chapter, DarkSky North Carolina. Some members in DarkSky NC also participate in Starry Skies South.</description></item><item><title>Partner Organizations</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/partners/</guid><description>Learn about the groups with whom we are partnered.</description></item><item><title>Members in the News</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/members-in-the-news/</guid><description>The above image was taken by Georgia member, Meaghan Gerard Walsh.
November 2022 Tom Berta&amp;rsquo;s article, Call to action for dark skies again is published in the Charleston City Paper.
September 2022 Tom Berta&amp;rsquo;s commentary, Bad street lighting is a problem. This is how we can fix it is posted in the Post and Courier.
June 2022 Our South Carolina coordinator, Tom Berta, is interviewed about light pollution in WCBD News 2 Charleston.</description></item><item><title>Acknowledgements</title><link>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.starryskiessouth.org/about/acknowledgements/</guid><description>The above photo was taken at Cheaha State Park during the event Discovering Dazzling New Depths of Dark Skies in April 2022.
Many thanks to&amp;hellip;
Ellyn Grady (University of Alabama at Birmingham) for providing tips and resources for getting our non-profit paperwork started the staff at Cheaha State Park, Oak Mountain State Park, University of Montevallo&amp;rsquo;s James Wylie Shepherd Observatory, and Samford University&amp;rsquo;s Christenberry Planetarium for partnering with us on public programming for International Dark-Sky Week 2022 dark-sky advocates Brent and Dawn Davis for supporting guidelines on dark-sky park creation procedures Maggie Johnston, Director of Wild Alabama, for supporting information on nonprofit organization and development within Alabama.</description></item></channel></rss>